RALPH MATTHEW C. MAGLAYA 3546 Lubiran St., Brgy 619, Sta. Mesa,

Manila

Email: maglayaralph26@gmail.com

Phone: +639306488574

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/immaglaya26 Portfolio: https://portfoliorap.netlify.app/



## **SUMMARY**

My commitment extends to continually learning about emerging technologies and staying abreast of the latest methods and tools within the industry. I actively seek to tackle real-world challenges, glean insights from experienced individuals, enhance my knowledge, and position myself for a successful career in the programing field.

### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

2020 to 2024 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Polytechnic University of the Philippines San Juan Campus, San Juan City, Metro Manila

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, PHP, Javascript, Java, Typescript

Frameworks: Express, Next JS, React JS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Redux, Laravel

**Libraries:** Node js, Jwt, Bcrpyt, Hash **Mobile Development:** Java, Kotlin

Database Management: MySql, Firebase, MongoDb,

Sql Version Control: Git

**DevOps:** Docker **Cloud Services:** AWS

Other: Postman, Github, Visual Studio Code, Figma, MySql Workbench, Xampp

# **AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS**

### Cum Laude (Oct. 2024) - Polytechnic University of the Philippines

• Awarded to candidates whose General Weighted Average is 1.50.

SEMINARS ATTENDED	
2023	Back end developer (BPI)
2024	Guardians of the Digital Realm: Navigating Cybersecurity Challenges in the modern age.
2024	System Integration and Security

#### **EXPERIENCES**

### On the Job Training (Programmer / Technical Support) - (April. 2024 - July 2024)

**Company:** Unison Computer Systems INC.

**Total Hours:** 500 hours

- Developed the Employee Directory System web application to promote Unison Computer System, Inc. personnel.
- Managed and maintained company operations, including computer systems and network cabling.
- Conducted system testing for employee applications and ensured website security thorough testing and vulnerability assessments.
- Completing 500 hours

### Web Developer (Freelance) - (Sept. 2024 - Nov. 2024)

## **Company:** Millennials Gadget

- Designed and developed an e-commerce website and a custom web-based system to enhance business operations.
- Deployed the website efficiently using GitHub pipelines and cPanel for smooth integration and management.
- Facilitated communication among company employees.
- Led the website design process, focusing on user experience and functionality.
- Applied Agile methodologies to ensure continuous improvement and timely project delivery.

### Web Developer (Freelance) - (Oct. 2023 - Jan. 2024)

### **Company:** Wisehunt

- Developed a web-based system for the company's store operations.
- Deployed the website using netlify for seamless hosting.
- Facilitated communication with the CEO of Wisehunt to align on project goals.
- Designed and implemented the company's website with a focus on user experience.
- Utilized Agile methodology to manage and better development processes.

# Freelance Developer - (2022 - 2024)

# Company: None

- Develop a website application for the capstone of the students, using frameworks web dev.
- Integrated payment gateways and implemented user authentication and authorization functionalities.
- Conducted testing and debugging to ensure the website's functionality and responsiveness across different devices.
- Designed and developed mobile app for a startup using Kotlin android studio

#### **Character Reference:**

Noel Gagolinan Roehl Espiritu

IT Manager, P-Tech Business Intelligence Lead

noelg1000@gmail.com roehlespiritu@gmail.com

09995134533 09985516246